Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today's lesson is
an advanced level lesson that means we'll
be speaking using our
normal English tone of voice
and using some very very
difficult vocabulary and phrases.
So this is really good
practice for all of you out there.
That's right, we're going to change a
little bit the dynamic of how it works.
We're not going to look
specifically at language
takeaway or fluency
builder, we're going
to talk about the topic,
we are going to pick
out a couple of different words and phrases
that are used in the dialogue, but we're
mainly going to talk,
just have a conversation
and you can just listen and study
a little bit of what we're saying.
So what is the topic today Marco?
Well today we're
going to talk about the
environment, specifically
about our carbon footprint.
Okay, that is the title
of today's lesson, I
encourage all of you
to listen to the context
of that phrase and we'll be back in a moment
to talk about what it and some of these
other phrases mean.
So what you guys take on all this
global warming hysteria and the media?
It's pretty serious
man, there have been
tons of scientific
studies and the scientific
community says that
the earth is heating up.
We need to make some
drastic changes to our
lifestyle if we want
to preserve our planet.
I don't know, it
sounds like a bunch of
mumbled jumble if you ask
me, the earth will save itself.
It survived the worst
disasters in the past, I
mean honestly, we live
in the boonies, there's
no way anyone here is
ever going to walk or bike to
work, especially in the winter
and we have no bus system.
My house is 40 years
old and it would take a
lot of money to get it refitted
to be green and energy efficient.
Well, I don't really
know if I believe in
global warming either
or whether or not it was
our doing or natural
change the earth is going
through, but you have
to admit that we're
living pretty irresponsibly
here in the West.
I guess.
I think the issue at
hand is sustainability.
We've only got this
one earth we can live on
and our resources are quickly disappearing
because of our own carelessness and our
inability to think of anyone but
ourselves and anything but the present.
So like I was saying, we need
to change the way we live.
We need to reduce our carbon footprint,
but it doesn't have to be that drastic.
Hybrid vehicles and
solar panels are too
expensive to be feasible
right now and we don't
have to be hippies living
off the land and buying
everything organic
either, though it helps.
I carpled to work every day
with some buddies of mine.
I have a rain barrel
outside my house, I used
to water my plants and
my lawn in the summer
and I make sure I always bring reusable
bags with me when I get my groceries.
And we just started
using biodegradable
plastic made from corn oil for
takeout orders at my family's restaurant.
Remember the three hours,
reduce, reduce, recycle.
Exactly.
It's just small, simple
changes like buying
energy saving light
bulbs, starting a compost
bin, recycling bottles
and papers, using
reusable water bottles, stop
using disposable cups and cutlery.
Like the ones we're drinking out of?
Yeah.
All right, we're back
so as you probably
guessed, carbon
footprint, it's pretty easy.
You're talking about
a footprint is the
evidence you leave if you're
walking on sand for example.
Exactly.
And if we talk about carbon, we're
talking about the element, right?
Carbon.
Yep.
Carbon is something that isn't
everything basically, it's organic.
But it can also, in
the case of a carbon
footprint, mean the amount
of maybe waste or damage
that we do to the earth
or to the environment.
Right.
So for example, you're driving
your car, we all know that
the gas that is emitted from
the exhaust pipe is CO2, right?
And that contains carbon.
So that's a way of seeing that
you're leaving a footprint of carbon.
You are damaging the atmosphere
a little bit by driving your car.
So in talking about a
carbon footprint, we
talk about having a low
carbon footprint, which
is good or a very high carbon
footprint, which is bad, right?
So there were a lot of interesting
things coming up in the dialogue.
One of the first things
was, well, the first
thing that they're
talking about in this
dialogue is they're
having kind of an argument
about whether or not global warming
and global climate change really exists.
Uh huh.
Yeah.
This is a very interesting
part because some
people say global warming is
happening, global warming is real.
And if people say, well, it's not real.
It's not really a problem.
This is just a phase
that the years will go
through and like
everything, it'll disappear.
Well, I agree with people who say that the
earth goes through phases because sometimes
there are centuries
that are hotter and
sometimes there are
centuries that are colder.
But I think it's undeniable
that there has been a large and
immediate global climate
change in the last maybe 20 years.
Yeah, we're definitely speeding
up maybe that cycle, right?
Exactly. And I think
what's great evidence
of this, and terrible
evidence of this is the
three earthquakes, massive earthquakes that
have happened in the last couple of months.
And I think that
earthquakes like last year
and like this year are
really, really important
reminders that we do as humans influence
the way that the world responds to us.
I think I always see
it as the earth kind of
just shaking its back kind
of saying like, get off me.
Stop it.
Exactly. I think that that's kind of
the way I see earthquakes sometimes.
But when they were talking
about, well, is it real, is it not?
They use a really
interesting phrase and
says, it sounds like a
bunch of mumbo jumbo.
mumbo jumbo.
So this is a way to say,
it sounds like a bunch
of garbage or it sounds
like a bunch of gibberish.
It sounds like a bunch
of people are talking
about something
that doesn't really exist.
So mumbo jumbo is basically
something that's not really real, but true.
I think, don't you
also, you can you use it
as somebody that's saying something
that you don't really understand?
Right.
So if maybe I'm talking
to you about something
that's very academic
and very scholarly,
you say f sounds like a
bunch of mumbo jumbo to me.
Exactly.
So that's what the person
said, the environmental
problems are a bunch
of mumbo jumbo.
But it was really interesting because they
were like, well, we have to save the earth
and well, and then there
was actually a phrase here
that was really kind of
hard for me to understand
when the person said, I mean,
honestly, we live in the bunnies, bunnies.
So what does it mean
by living in the bunnies?
This is a very common word to hear in spoken
English, especially with young people.
Bunnies means we live
far away from civilization,
we live far away from cities,
we live far away from everything.
So maybe these people live in
the countryside or in a small village.
And they don't feel like they're affected
by what people in the big cities do.
Okay.
So if you say, oh, I live in the bunnies,
you're just saying, I live really far.
Really far away.
So this is a very common
American word, I think.
You can also say, boondocks, which
is like that movie, boondocks, saints.
But boondocks and
boonies means very far away.
So I could say, Marco, I'm not going
to drive out to your house for a party.
You live in the bunnies.
Do you have any other ways of you
can say that you live really far away?
You live in Egypt.
Which for us in America
is a very, very far away.
Sometimes we say, the youngs, the
youngs, people in New Zealand say that.
I've also heard people say, oh, you
live where the wind turns around.
Really?
I like that one.
So you live so far.
Oh, God.
You live where the wind turns around.
The end of the earth.
Exactly.
Wow.
So well, there are a lot of
different ways of saying that.
So they were talking about different aspects
of the environment, like that we heard
the word green or energy efficient.
OK.
So basically what
they're doing is they're
talking about some of
the things they've heard
in the media maybe, or on TV, about what
people are supposed to be doing, you know?
These are very abstract.
That means these are
very kind of big terms.
Go green or be more energy efficient.
Yeah.
I've heard this, like,
for example, when
people say, oh, you
have to be more green or
go green, that means more
friendly towards the ecosystem, right?
That's right.
General suggestion,
and we can talk about
specifics in a minute,
but this is a very general
suggestion for thinking about the
environment and doing things to help it.
And so go green or be green is a
way to be more environmentally friendly.
We also have using energy efficient
computers or light bulbs or TVs.
Right.
The third thing that
they talk about, and this is
something that comes
up a lot, is sustainability.
Yeah.
That's a big word that a lot of
people like to use in this type of topics.
That's sustainability.
Right.
So sustainability comes
from the word to sustain.
That means to hold out
over time or to continue.
So you think about something.
Maybe sustainability
is, I think in many cases,
about doing or having
habits, doing things
that you can continue
to do for a long time.
For example, driving a
big SUV to work every
day is not keeping in mind sustainability,
because one day there will be no oil.
So then what do we do?
Right.
So that's not a sustainable action.
Sustainable actions mean that we have
less impact, negative impact on the world.
Right.
So basically, what
you're trying to do is to
sustain, which means to hold, to
withstand these habits, for example.
Right.
So when you talk about
a sustainable ecosystem,
it means that it has
everything it needs
and it can continue to work
for a very, very long time.
Right.
So you can also talk
about sustainable
developments, which we talk about
in aid and giving aid to other countries.
So sustainable
development is trying to help
other countries or other people in ways that
they can continue to do for a long time.
It's also very popular with tourism.
They talk about sustainable tourism.
Right.
That means thinking
about the environment
and having tourism
that can last forever, not
tourism that will destroy the
environment because it's very harmful.
It's a very interesting topic.
And as you say, it's
used in a wide range of
cases, sustainable
development, sustainable
projects, sustainable tourism, there are a
lot of different ways that people use this.
But it's basically the same thing, right?
It's, in essence, it refers to that.
Yes.
Keeping something going over time.
But I think the big
question here is, if you want
to go green, if you want to be
environmentally friendly, what do you do?
Because it's not about big ideas.
It's about specifics.
It's about changing your
everyday actions, right?
Right.
So these guys had a couple of ideas.
Yeah.
They came up with
something like, for example,
hybrid vehicles, which
is a big thing now.
Basically, hybrid means two, right?
It's a combination of two or more.
That's right.
So, you know, the stinks
in Egypt, that's a hybrid.
Right.
Between a man and a lion.
Exactly.
So a hybrid vehicle basically
uses gasoline, but also electricity.
So they're very, they're
very, very efficient
because they're
quiet and they're quiet.
And usually where
you use up most of your
gasoline is in traffic
because your car is on,
you're accelerating, you're breaking,
you're accelerating, you're breaking.
So in this case, I think
hybrid vehicles run
on the electric engine
until they hit, I think
it's 30 miles per hour.
And once you surpass that, then it switches
to the gas engine, which obviously if you
have a constant high
speed, it uses, it's more
efficient, the combustion
of the gasoline.
Exactly.
So a good example of a hybrid
vehicle is the toilet of Prius.
Right.
I think it was like the first
one commercially available.
But now they have
all kinds and they're
actually trying to make
entirely electric cars.
So lots of things to
watch out for there,
but they also talked about
something for the house.
Right.
So if you want to not just have a nice car
that is environmentally friendly, but also
to do things with your house,
what can you put on your roof?
I think we've seen a lot of these,
these are called solar panels.
Okay.
Solar has to do with the sun.
So solar power, solar panel, that
means energy that comes from the sun.
So the sun and a
panel is like a pad or like
some kind of device that can
take the energy from the sun.
Yeah.
It's really, really good.
Basically, you know, in
some places you have
anywhere between 8
to 12 hours of sunlight.
So the whole day, these
panels are absorbing energy.
You can store them maybe in
batteries and then just use them later.
So basically you
don't really need to use
electricity that comes from
coal or from nuclear power plants.
Right.
You want to turn on a light, it
doesn't really use up a lot of electricity.
And there's no waste.
It's all clean.
So my question for you, does Ecuador
have a lot of solar panels everywhere?
Because you guys have so
much sunlight down there.
We don't really have a lot of them.
It's not a big commercial thing yet.
But there are a lot of
projects going around
to help implement
these things a lot better.
For example, taking
these technologies to the
countryside where people don't have access
to electricity by means of cables, right?
So they're implementing that
there, getting them to use it.
But it's still expensive.
That's the problem
with solar panels is
that, of course, it's an
energy-efficient way of going.
It'll save you money in the long run, but
upfront you get to spend a lot of money.
And here's a good way of sustaining.
If someone in the
countryside has solar panels
in their house, it's a self-sustaining
way to produce energy.
Exactly.
You don't have to depend on another place.
Yeah.
Actually, this is a very popular
thing in many developed countries.
I remember when I
was living in Chile, big
buildings were being
marketed as energy-efficient
and green by showing that
they can be self-sustained.
So basically they would
have solar panels on the roof.
They would collect
sunlight all day and then
they had big batteries that would
store this energy and then you can use it.
They were more efficient into
keeping heat or keeping the cold.
And also what we saw in the
vocab, they also had was rain barrels.
So basically collecting
water from the rain.
And then they can use
this water, obviously,
through a filtering
system in order to be able
to drink it or to wash
your clothes and stuff.
But basically they
would say that it could
reduce your carbon
footprint by more than 50%.
And also the amount of
money you would spend,
because you wouldn't spend
so much money in water.
You wouldn't spend so much money
on electricity or gas and things like this.
That's awesome.
Well, one of the biggest concerns as far as
environmentalism is water, where water will
come from in 50 years because there is a
limited amount of freshwater in the world.
And if we can reuse rainwater
and collect it, I think it's brilliant.
So a barrel basically
is like a big container,
circular, it's like a
circle, and it stands
up on the ground or on a roof.
And it's brilliant
because if you have a rain
barrel that collects
all this rain and you
have solar panels, basically you don't need
gas or electricity to take a warm shower.
You just have the solar
panels that can heat
up the rain barrel water and
there you have a warm water.
You have sun-kissed warmth
but you have like fresh rainwater.
But the whole water is
just a very popular topic.
I recommend that any of our listeners read,
there's a very interesting article that
talks about don't worry
about petroleum running
out in 50 years, we're probably going
to run out of our water before that.
And they project droughts
and huge famine in
places like India, like in the
Middle East, even places of China.
Really?
Well, not so scary
anyone, but yeah, it's
interesting reading
though, yeah, it's really good.
Very serious stuff.
Well, the last thing
that I think we should
talk about before we listen to today's
audio file again is the compost bin.
This is maybe something
that's hard to understand
for someone who's
never seen one before.
But basically compost is, well, the verb is
compost, too compost, but it's also a noun.
But a lot of people,
they don't want to throw
away their food and
their organic material
things like flowers and food and biodegradable
things, they actually reuse them.
So basically they have
a space in the backyard
of the house where
they throw away all
the old food, nothing plastic,
nothing non-biodegradable.
And that over time turns into
fertilizer or mulch for their gardens.
So basically you're putting
it back into the earth.
Yeah, no, this is a very good option.
And I remember
seeing that even in Brazil,
they have huge compost bins or compost
places that they fill up with this garbage.
And obviously things that
decompose start to emit methane gas.
So they've found a way to harness this gas,
transport it through tubes, and start using
it, so actually having gas
stoves with this methane gas.
That's brilliant.
So you can get two uses,
fertilizer and methane gas.
Yeah, so there are a
lot of options there to
go green to do your
part to help the earth.
Wow.
So let's listen again to the
dialogue that we had today.
Hopefully we've cleared up some of
the things that we're confusing for you.
And we'll be back in just a moment.
So what's your guys taking on all this
global warming hysteria and the media?
It's pretty serious, man.
There have been tons of
scientific studies and the
scientific community says
that the earth is heating up.
We need to make some
drastic changes to our
lifestyle if we want
to preserve our planet.
I don't know.
It sounds like a bunch of
mumbled jumble if you ask me.
The earth will save itself.
It survived the worst
disasters in the past.
I mean, honestly, we live in the boonies.
There's no way anyone
here is ever going to
walk or bike to work,
especially in the winter.
And we have no bus system.
My house is 40 years
old and it would take a
lot of money to get it refitted
to be green and energy efficient.
Well, I don't really
know if I believe in
global warming either
or whether or not it was
our doing or natural change
the earth is going through.
But you have to admit that we're living
pretty irresponsibly here in the West.
I guess.
I think the issue at
hand is sustainability.
We've only got this
one earth we can live on.
And our resources are
quickly disappearing
because of our own
carelessness and our inability
to think of anyone but ourselves
and anything but the present.
So like I was saying, we need
to change the way we live.
We need to reduce our carbon footprint.
But it doesn't have to be that drastic.
Hybrid vehicles and solar panels are
too expensive to be feasible right now.
But we don't have
to be hippies living off
the land and buying everything
organic either though it helps.
I carpool to work every day
with some buddies of mine.
I have a rain barrel outside my house.
I used to water my plants
and my lawn in the summer.
And I make sure I always bring reusable
bags with me when I get my groceries.
And we just started
using biodegradable
plastic made from corn oil for
takeout orders at my family's restaurant.
Remember the three hours,
reduce, reduce, recycle.
Exactly.
It's just small, simple
changes like buying
energy saving light
bulbs, starting a compost
bin, recycling bottles
and papers using reusable
water bottles, stop using
disposable cups and cutlery.
Like the ones we're drinking out of.
Yeah.
All right, we're back.
So it's a very interesting
topic, very debatable.
We have Earth Day coming up, I think.
You have to turn off
your lights for an hour.
That's right.
Earth hour, Earth Day.
So remember, reduce,
reuse, recycle the three R's.
Think about the way that you use
things and try and reuse them if you can.
Yeah.
It's a very good topic.
We want to know what
you think about it and
also if you have any
suggestions or any comments
about future advanced lessons, why
don't you tell us, come to EnglishPod.com.
And we'll see everyone there.
Bye.
[MUSIC PLAYING]